اَلْحَمْدُ لله وَالصَّلَاةُ وَالسَّلَامُ عَلى سَيِّدِنَا محمد وَعَلَى اَلِهِ وَصَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ تَسْلِيْمًا كَثِيْرا * أمَّا بَعْد
This is our second session, on the life of Sayyedina(سيدنا) Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه.
We talked in our previous session on some background information and an introduction to this series.
Now we'll talk about the family of Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه.
His first wife was Qateela Bint Abdul Uzzah(قتيله بنت عبد العزة), whom he divorced, in the time of Jahiliyyah(جَاهلِيَّة).
There's a difference of opinion on whether she later became a Muslim or not
and she was the mother of Asmaa(اسماء) and Abdullah(عبدالله).
So Qateela(قتيله) was the mother of Asmaa(اسماء) and Abdullah(عبدالله), that's his first wife.
He was also married to Umm Romaan Bint Aamir(ام رومان بنت عامر)
she was one of the early Muslims.
And she was the mother of Abdur Rahman(عبدالرحمن) and Ayeshaرضي الله عنهم.
His third wife was Asmaa Bint Umais(اسماء بنت عميس),
now Asmaa Bint Umais(اسماء بنت عميس) was the wife of Jafar Ibn Abi Talib(جعفر ابن ابي طالب)
the brother of Ali(علي), the cousin of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
And Asmaa(اسماء) made Hijrah(هجرة) with her husband Jafar(جعفر) to Abyssinia
and we know that Jafar(جعفر) is the Ameer(امير) of the Muslims, in Abyssinia
and they stayed there for a very long time.
And they only came back during the time of Ghazwat Khaybar(غزوة خيبر),
which was towards the latter part of the time of Rasool Allah ﷺ in Madina.
And then Jafar Ibn Abi Talib(جعفر ابن ابي طالب) was second in command in the Battle of Mu'ta(مؤته),
Rasool Allah ﷺ later on sent him in the eighth year of Hijrah(هجرة),
as second in command after Zaid Bin Harissa(زيد بن حارثه) in the Battle of Mu'ta(مؤته).
So, when Zaid Bin Harissa(زيد بن حارثه) was killed.
The one, who assumed leadership after him was Jafar Ibn Abi Talib(جعفرابن ابي طالب).
And he was carrying the flag or the banner of war.
So his right hand was cut, he held it with the left hand
the left hand was cut, so he held it with whatever was left from his arms
that was also chopped.
So he hugged it, until he fell down dead in the end.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ said, Allahسبحانه وتعالى has replaced his two arms with two wings for him to fly with them in paradise.
So, his wife Asmaa Bint Umais(اسماء بنت عميس) was widowed.
It was the tradition of the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم, not to leave any women single.
If a woman is divorced, if a woman is widowed or if a woman didn't get married early
the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم would not leave such a sister alone.
So, Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه married Asmaa Bint Umais(اسماء بنت عميس)
and she was the mother of Muhammad Ibn Abi Bakr(محمد ابن ابي بكر).
The fourth wife of Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه was Habiba Bint Kharijah(حبيبه بنت خارجه).
And she is from among Al-Ansaar(الانصار), specifically from the tribe of Al-Khazraj رضي الله عنهم.
And she used to live in a place called As-Sanhe(السنح), which is, if we would say the suburbs of Madina.
So, it was a little far away from the center of town.
And that's where Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) was, when Rasool Allah ﷺ passed away.
So, that's why he came on late, after the news has already spread.
We'll talk about that, because he has spent that night with his wife in As-Sanhe(السنح),
she was the mother of Umm Kalsoom Bint Abi Bakr(ام كلثوم بنت ابي بكر).
So these are the wives of Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابو بكر الصديق).
Again Qateela Bint Abd Ul Uzzah(قتيله بنت عبد العزة), Umm Romaan Bint Aamir(ام رومان بنت عامر)
Asmaa Bint Umais(اسماء بنت عميس) and Habiba Bint Kharijah(حبيبه بنت خارجه).
His children, the eldest was Abdur Rahman Bin Abi Bakr(عبد الرحمن بن ابي بكر).
He became Muslim quite late compared to the rest of the family
he was the last person among the family to become Muslim.
In fact he fought against the Muslims in the Battle of Badr(بدر).
Abdur Rahman Ibn Abi Bakr(عبد الرحمن بن ابي بكر) was known as one of the courageous and strong fighters of Quraish(قریش), that was his reputation.
He only became Muslim after Sulh Al-Hudaybiyyah(صلح الحديبيه).
Then he had Abdullah Bin Abi Bakr رضي الله عنه
and Abdullah(عبدالله), played a critical role in Al-Hijrah(الهجرة) and we'll talk about that.
Now Abdullah Bin Abi Bakr(عبد الله بن ابي بكر) was injured by an arrow during the siege of At-Taef(الطائف).
However, it didn't kill him immediately, he only died during the Khilafah(خلافة) of his father, Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه.
So, the injury was critical but he lived in that injured states for some time and then eventually he died.
So his death is considered Shahadah(شهادة) because it was due to the injury caused by that arrow.
Later on, the story goes that Abu Bakr As-Siddique(أبوبكرالصديق), he retained that arrow with him, he kept the arrow
and when he was Khalifah(خليفه) and he met with the delegation from At-Taef(اَلطَّائِف).
He brought out that arrow and he asked them, who does this arrow belong to?
So one of them not knowing what was the reason of this question?
He said, after he took a close look at the arrow, he said:
This arrow is mine؛ I'm the one who sharpened it
I'm the one who prepared it, I'm the one who stuck the feathers to it
and I am the one who shot with it.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه said: And that's the arrow that killed my son, Abdullah(عبدالله).
So the man said: Well, Alhamdulillah(ألحمدلله),
who has honored your son by me, killing him and making him a Shaheed(شَهِيد)
and Alhamdulillah(ألحمدلله) who has then guided me and made me a Muslim.
Muhammad Ibn Abu Bakr(محمد إبن ابوبكر), and his mother was Asma Bint Umais(أسماءبنت عميس).
Muhammad Ibn Abu Bakr(محمد إبن ابوبكر) was brought up by Ali Ibn Abi Talib(علي ابن ابي طالب)
because of the relationships.
See Asma bint Umais(أسماءبنت عميس) was the ex-wife of his brother.
So when she had her son from Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه, Muhammad(محمد).
Ali ibn Talib(علي ابن ابي طالب) is the one who raised him up
and they had a very close relationship.
Infact in the time of Khilafah(خِلَافَه) of Ali Ibn Abi Talib(علي ابن ابي طالب), he appointed Muhammad(محمد) as his governor over Egypt.
Asma bint Abi Bakr رضی اللہ عنھا the older daughter of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر), she was older than Ayesha رضي الله عنها.
Asma Bint Abi Bakr(أسماء بنت أبي بكر) also played a very important role in Al-Hijrah(ألهجرى).
She was called Zaat An-Nataqain(ذات النطاقين),
the woman of the two belts, and Nataq(نطاق) is a belt that woman used to use, on their waist.
It's a belt made out of cloth, it was a piece of cloth that they would wrap on their waists.
Now, when she was delivering food to Rasool Allah ﷺ and Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) in the cave,
she didn't have anything to put the food in.
So what she did is, she tied that belt into two pieces,
and she put the food into those two pieces and delivered it to Rasool Allah ﷺ and Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
So it was Rasool Allah ﷺ, who called her, gave her the name of Zaat An-Nataqain(ذات النطاقين).
This name was given to her by Rasool Allah ﷺ, Zaat An-Nataqain(ذات النطاقين).
Now Asma Bint Abi Bakr(أسماء بنت أبي بكر) got married to a Az-Zubair Bin Awwam(ألزبير بن عوام)
one of the 10 who were given the glad tidings of Jannah(جنة).
Az-Zubair Bin Awwam رضي الله عنه was a warrior.
So he was a bit harsh with Asma Bint Abi Bakr رضي الله عنها
and he would have her do a lot of laborious work at home.
So she went and complained to her father.
She said: My husband,
and that was the nature of Az-Zubair Bin Awwam(ألزبير بن عوام),
I mean Az-Zubair Bin Awwam(ألزبير بن عوام) was a tough man.
One of his stories, he once hit, one of the enemy soldiers and he split him into two pieces.
And the sword went down after cutting the men into two pieces, and it cut the saddle of the horse.
So the saddle fell from both sides.
The Sahabah(صحابه), who saw that they said;
You have a powerful sword, O Zubair(زبير).
So Az-Zubair Bin Awwam(ألزبير بن عوام) responded by saying it is the arm that is powerful, not the sword.
There was a well known Faris(فارس), warrior from Quraish(قُرَيْشْ)
they used to call him, Al-Kabsh(ألكبش).
He was big, well built fighter.
He got into a duel with Az-Zubair Bin Awwam(ألزبير بن عوام) in one of the battles,
and this man was covered in Iron, covered in armory from head to toe.
So Az-Zubair Bin Awwam(ألزبير بن عوام) with his spear hit him in the opening for the eye.
See that's the only place that is open, in this armory.
He is covered in steel from head to toe with only small holes for him to see through.
So Az-Zubair(ألزبير) hit him with the spear in that opening but the blade of the spear was big, so it couldn't go through.
So Az-Zubair Bin Awwam(ألزبير بن عوام) pushed it so hard.
And then he stepped on it with his foot, until he got it through and it killed the man.
But when they pulled out the Spear, the blade which was a thick blade was bent.
Now when the Sahabah(صحابه) saw that, it was amazing, I mean you have this thick blade of steel bent.
So Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه wanted to keep it as a souvenir and he gave it to him
and when he died, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) wanted to keep it, so he kept it as a souvenir.
And then it moved from Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) to Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان)
and then later on, it was inherited by the son of Zubair(ألزبير), Abdullah(عبدلله), and he kept it with him, until he died.
I mean as a memory from his father.
So Asma Bint Abi Bakr(أسماء بنت أبي بكر) went to her father complaining about her husband.
She said: He's having me to do all of this Labouress work,
cleaning his house, taking care of his kids, grinding the flour
and then he has me feed his horse, take care of his horse, and all of that and it's too much for me,
she was asking for a servant and some help.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه could have told her take him to court and ask for a divorce.
But what he said.?
He said: If a woman has a righteous husband, she will be his wife in Jannah(جنة).
So my daughter, be patient! My daughter be patient.
Because Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه, knew that Az-Zubair Bin Awwam is one of the 10 who are given the glad tidings of Jannah(جنة).
So it's an honor for his daughter to be with such a man.
So he told her: Be patient! Be patient! And she was.
Asma Bint Abi Bakr رضي الله عنها reached, actually she passed the age of 100 years
without losing any of her mental abilities and without losing even one tooth,
and she died in Makkah in year 73 of Al-Hijrah(هجرى).
And she narrated 56 Ahadith(احاديث) of the Ahadith(احاديث) of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Next, Ayesha(عائشه), the most beloved person, to Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Ayesha رضي الله عنها, when Ash-Sha'abi(ألشعبي) would narrate her Hadith(حديث).
He would say, this Hadith(حديث) is narrated by Al-Habiba Bint Al-Habib(ألحبيبة بنت ألحبيب),
the beloved, the daughter of the Beloved.
She was beloved to Rasool Allah ﷺ and her father was beloved to Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Rasool Allah ﷺ when he would be in a gathering, he would look the Sahabah(صحابه) in the eye and give them attention.
Amr Bin Al-Aas(عَمْرُو بِن اَلْعَاص) was a new Muslim
and Rasool Allah ﷺ, when he would speak in a gathering he would look at Amr Bin Al-Aas(عَمْرُو بِن اَلْعَاص) and speak to him directly.
So Amr Bin Al-Aas رضي الله عنه felt that Rasool Allah ﷺ loves me so much.
I mean, he's looking at me out of all these people, it means, that he likes me.
So Amr Bin Al-Aas رضي الله عنه later on, went to Rasool Allah ﷺ and said;
Who is the most beloved person to you?
So Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Ayesha رضي الله عنها
Amr Bin Al-Aas(عَمْرُو بِن اَلْعَاص) said: What about from among the men who is the most beloved from the men to you?
Rasool Allah ﷺ said;
ومن الرجال أبوها
And from among the men, her father.
So Ayesha رضي الله عنها was the most beloved of the wives of Rasool Allah ﷺ to him, after Khadeejah رضي الله عنها.
Ayesha رضي الله عنها, she married Rasool Allah ﷺ at the age of six.
It was the destiny of Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ that He marries Ayesha رضي الله عنها to Rasool Allah ﷺ
in order that she become the greatest woman's scholar of this Ummah(امة).
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ has destined that Ayesha رضي الله عنها will be the one,
who will convey the Ahadith(احاديث) of Rasool Allah ﷺ to Ummah(امة).
Therefore, Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ married Rasool Allah ﷺ to Ayesha(عائشه),
at the same age we put our children in school, at the age of six.
Because she was to become the student of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
And for her to fulfill that duty of teaching the Ummah(امة)
and conveying the knowledge of Hadith(حديث) to us, and she didn't have any children
so by the age of 18, Rasool Allah ﷺ has already passed away, and she has no children,
so she could devote her time, full time to teaching the Hadith(حديث) of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Therefore, Ayesha رضي الله عنها ranks Number four among the top narrators of Hadith(حديث).
Among the top narrators of Hadith(حديث), Ayesha رضي الله عنها is Number four.
There is no book of Hadith(حديث) that can be called the Book of Hadith(حديث) if it doesn't have the Hadith(حديث) of Ayesha(عائشه),
there is no book of Fiqh(فقه) that could be considered the book of Fiqh(فقه)
if it doesn't have the Fatawa(فتوي) of Ayesha(عائشه).
And there is no book of Tafseer(تفسير) that can be called Tafseer(تفسير),
if it doesn't have the Tafseer(تفسير) of Ayesha رضي الله عنها .
Therefore Ayesha رضي الله عنها is the greatest woman scholar that ever lived in this world.
Ayesha رضي الله عنها narrated 2210 Ahadith(احاديث),
and Bukhari(بخاريْ) and Muslim(مسلم) agreed on 147,
Bukhari(بخاري) narrated 54 Ahadith(احاديث) from Ayesha(عائشه) Muslim(مسلم) narrated 69.
Ayesha رضي الله عنها died at the age of 63, in year, 57 of Al-Hijrah(الهجرة).
Umm Kalsoom(ام كلثوم), the youngest of the children of Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) and she was born after he died.
Before the death of Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه,
he was speaking to his daughter Ayesha(عائشه) and he told her, these are you two brothers, and these are your two sisters.
So, Ayesha رضي الله عنها said, I know my two brothers
and here is my one sister, Asmaa(اسماء) who is the other one.
Abu Bakr As-Siddiqueرضي الله عنه said;
The other one is the one in the womb of my wife Habiba(حبيبه) and I believe that it's going to be a daughter.
Now that was before he died and it turned out, as he thought.
So, a few months after he passed away his wife delivered Umm Kalsoom رضي الله عنها.
And Umm Kalsoom(ام كلثوم) was then married to Talha Bin Ubaid Illah(طلحه بن عبيد الله),
another of the 10, who were given the glad tidings of Jannah(جنة).
Infact Az-Zubair(الزبير) and Talha(طلحه) had such a close relationship and a brotherly relationship,
you rarely can mention the name of one without mentioning the name of the other.
So Az-Zubair(الزبير) and Talha(طلحه) always go together and they even died together
in the Waqa'a(وقع) of Al-Jamal(الجمل), in the battle of Al-Jamal(الجمل).
So, Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه had his daughter Asmaa(اسماء) married to Az-Zubair(الزبير),
and then after he(ابوبكر) passed away, Talha Bin Ubaid Illah(طلحه بن عبيد الله) married his daughter Umm Kalsoom(ام كلثوم).
Therefore both Az-Zubair(الزبير) and Talha(طلحه) had a family relationship with Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه.
Now she didn't live with her husband for very long because,
Talha Bin Ubaid Illah(طلحه بن عبيد الله) was killed in Waqat Ul Jamal(وقعة الجمل).
So this is the family of Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه.
THE ISLAM OF ABU BAKR(ابوبكر).
And I will narrate the statement of Ibn Kathir(ابن كثير) in Al-Bidayah Wan Nihayah(البدائية ونهائيه),
Al-Bidayah Wan Nihayah(البدائية ونهائيه) is the famous monumental work of the great Imam(امام) and scholar Ibn Kathir Damishqi(ابن كثير دمشقي).
The name of this encyclopedia is, The Beginning And The End.
And it's literally the beginning to the end.
He started from creation, and he ended with when the people entered into Jannah(جنة) and Naar(النار).
So he started by talking about the story of creation,
and then he talks about the stories of the Ambiyaa(انبياء)
and then the Seerah(سيرة) of Muhammadﷺ, and then all the events of history, up to his time.
And then he spoke about the signs of the Day of Judgment,
the day of Judgment, and then Jannah(جنة) and Naar(النار).
One of the best works of history compiled by the Muslim scholars.
Anyway, he says about this, the Islam of Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه, he says;
The first woman to become Muslim was Khadijah رضي الله عنها,
the first child to become Muslim was Ali Bin Abi Talib رضي الله عنه,
the first slave to become Muslim was Zaid Bin Harissa رضي الله عنه,
and the first free man to become Muslim was Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه.
And his Islam was more beneficial to the religion than all of the above.
Because he became Muslim when he was a noble man in the society.
So he used his nobility, his strength, his abilities, his skills and his wealth
for the service of the religion, and for the service of Muhammadﷺ.
كَانَ صَدْرً مُقَدِّمًا فِيْ قَوْمِه
He says that he was a noble man, and he was a leader among his people.
وإسلامه كان أنفع  من إسلام من تقدم زكرهم
إذ كان صدرًا معظمًا رعيسًا في قريش
مكرمًا وَصاحبهم و مالٍ وداعيً إلإسلام
وكان محببًا متعلفًا يبزل المال في طاعة الله ورسوله
Rasool Allah ﷺ, when he gave Daw'ah(دعوة) to Abu Bakr As-Siddiqueرضي الله عنه,
he told him Allahعَزّوجَلّ has sent me as a messenger to warn mankind, and I invite you to Islam.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه immediately without any hesitation, without any second thoughts, said:
أشهد و الله اله الا الله، واشهدو ان محمد الرسول الله
There's a statement that,
لكل حصانٍ قبوة
For every horse, there's a stumble.
Every horse, no matter how good it is, will one day stumble it happens with the best horses.
But they say, with Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه, that stumble, never came.
With the other invitations that were given by Rasool Allah ﷺ to the Sahabah(صحابه)
with some of them, it took seconds, with some of them, it took days
with some it took months, with some it took years,
like with Khalid Bin Waleed رضي الله عنه, he had to think about Islam for years,
Amr Bin Aas رضي الله عنه, even the son of Abu Bakr رضي الله عنه,
Abdur Rahmaan Bin Abi Bakr(عبدالرحمن بن ابي بكر), he only became Muslim during Sulh Al-Hudaybiyyah(صلح الحديبيه).
But with Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه as soon as Rasool Allah ﷺ delivered the invitation to him,
immediately Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه became Muslim.
How come.?
If we may ask the question.
Was it because Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) was a type of person, who could change his mind easily?
Was it because he was a person, who could buy into an argument easily?
That wasn't the personality of Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه, because if you look at the time of his Khilafah(خلافه),
you could see that! Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه can be as firm as one could be.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه in a few instances would stand up against everyone else,
and would hold firm to his opinion and at the end it would turn out to be, the right opinion.
Like what's happened with the army of Osama Bin Zaid رضي الله عنه
and what happened with Qitaal(قتال) with Murtaddeen(مرتدين).
There was a lot of resistance from the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم
and they used every convincing argument they could use,
but in the end Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه, his argument prevailed.
So, how come Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه, immediately accepted the invitation of Rasool Allah ﷺ?
The reason is because he was ready for it.
He maybe has already thought about that a lot, so he didn't need to sit on it.
He didn't need to give it a second thought.
He didn't need to wait and give it consideration, he was already prepared.
Ayesha رضي الله عنها says my father never ever prostrated to an idol,
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه was never a Mushrik(مشرك).
He said: When I was young, my father took me to the idols, where the idols were gathered.
And he told me,
هذه الهتك شمل العوالي
These are your noble gods and then he left me.
That is how religion is passed on, parents, deliver their religion to their children.
So, the father Abu Qahafah(ابوقحافه) is taking his son Abu Bakr(أبوبكر) to introduce him to the idols, he's saying,
هذه الهتك شمل العوالي
These are your noble gods, so worship them and then he left his son.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه was speaking to the idols and was saying: Can you benefit me,
can you harm me, can you eat, can you drink.
And then he said: I'm not gonna worship idols that cannot hear or see, when he was a child.
So, he was ready for it.
So, you would find that the people who immediately accepted the message, were the people, who were at some level of preparation
they were waiting for it.
See with some people, they were waiting for it but they could not get there
because they needed a Nabi(نبي) to deliver to them.
Abu Dhar Al-Ghiffaari رضي الله عنه, when he left his people in Ghifaar(غفار),
they were not businessmen like the people of Makkah nor were they in agriculture like the people of Madina,
their profession was raiding caravans, stealing.
Abu Dhar Al-Ghiffaari(ابوذرالغفاري), his Fitrah(فطرة), his natural disposition told him that this is wrong so he left his people.
When he was passing next to Makkah, he heard the news that there was someone in Makkah who's claiming to be a prophet.
So he sent his brother, Unais(انيس) to check it out.
Unais(انيس) came back to him and said that people say that he's a magician, some say that he's ... about Muhammadﷺ.
Some say, he's a liar, some say he's a poet, some say he is insane,
he's possessed with demons, he is this, he is a fortune teller, he is this and that.
Abu Dhar Al-Ghiffaari رضي الله عنه said,
ما أغنَيْتَ عَنِّيْ شيئا
You haven't done me any good, I'm going to go and check it out myself.
And he went into Makkah and he had a meeting with Rasool Allah ﷺ and he immediately became a Muslim. Why.?
Abu Dhar Al-Ghiffaari رضي الله عنه says about himself
that I used to pray to Allahعَزّوجَلّ, two years before I became a Muslim.
Two years before I became a Muslim, I used to pray to Allahعَزّوجَلّ, so they asked him,
How would you do that.?
He would say: I would face whichever direction, I can.
And I would pray, how ever, I could.
He didn't know how to pray, Salawaat Ul Khams(صلواة الخمس),
because to do that you need the guidance of the Nabi(نبي) - Muhammadﷺ.
But his Fitrah(فطرة) was telling him that the truth is the oneness of Allahعَزّوجَلّ.
Salman Al-Farisi رضي الله عنه, he immediately accepted the message of Muhammadﷺ because he was waiting for it.
So that was the stage of Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه, he was waiting for it,
therefore as soon as the invitation came, he immediately accepted it.
Like when you're waiting for something so bad and
as soon as the invitation comes, you immediately respond.
Not only in terms of Tauheed(توحيد), the character of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر), his character, his makeup was good from the beginning.
Ayesha رضي الله عنه says about her father, that my father did not drink alcohol in Islam, or before Islam
he didn't drink Khamr(خمر).
In another narration Ayesha رضي الله عنها says that
my father and Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان إبن عفان) called Alcohol Haraam(حرام) from the time of Jahiliyyah(جَاهلِيَّة),
They did not drink from the time of Jahiliyyah(جَاهلِيَّة), and they considered it to be Haram(حرام), illegal.
Now why did Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه take that position towards alcohol?
Ayesha رضي الله عنها narrates that once, my father was asked by some Muslims.
Did you drink Khamr(خمر), did you drink wine, when you were a Mushrik(مشرك).?
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه said:
"أعوذ بالله"
I seek refuge in Allah, they said: How come you say that.?
He said: Because,
كنت أسونوإرضي ومُروعتي
I used to guard my honor and my dignity.
Because drinking violates the honor of a person and violates the dignity of a person.
And Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه said: One day, I saw a man, who was drunk.
This man would stick his hand in stool, feces, and he would take some of it and try to eat it.
But when he would pull his hand close to his mouth.
He would smell, the bad smell of his stool so he would push his hand away,
but then he would drive his hand closer, and the smell would repel him,
and he would keep on doing that, and the smell is repulsing him, otherwise he would eat from it.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه said;
"إنَّ هذا رجل لا يعقل"
This man has no sense, he lost his mind.
And that is what alcohol does to you, you lose your mind.
So, Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه said;
كنت أسونوإرضي ومُروعتي
I used to protect my dignity and my honor and he did this, before Islam.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه, also had the character of a Da'iyah(داعية), a caller to Islam.
And this is what Ibn Kathir(ابن كثير) talks about.
Abu Bakr As-siddique(أبوبكرالصديق), when he came into Islam, he came in with everything that he had,
he put everything on the line for the service of Islam.
Very soon after he became Muslim, he started inviting others towards Islam
and look at the names that he brought into the fold of the religion.
Uthman Ibn Affan رضي الله عنه, Az-Zubair Bin Awwam(الزبيربن عوام),
Talha Bin Ubaid Illah(طلحه بن عبيدالله), Abdur Rahman Ibn Auf(عبدالرحمن ابن عوف),
Sa'ad Ibn Abi Waqas(سعدابن ابي وقاص) and Abi Obaidah Amr Bin Jarrah(ابوعبيده عمروبن جراح).
All of these five are among the 10, who are given glad tidings of Jannah(جنة),
and they became Muslim through the Da'wah(دعوة) of Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه.
Therefore, everything they do, a copy of that will go into the account of Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه on the Day of Judgment.
Five of the 10, who were given glad tidings of Jannah(جنة) became Muslim through the Da'wah(دعوة) of Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابو بكر الصديق),
not only that but there are many others, I just mentioned the names of these
because these are among the 10, but also Al-Arqam Ibn Al-Arqam(ارقم ابن الارقم)
became Muslim, due to the Da'wah(دعوة) of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر),
the house where Rasool Allah ﷺ would meet in Makkah, Daar Ul Arqam(دارالارقم).
Abu Salamah Bin Abd Asad(ابوسلمه بن عبدالاسد) also became Muslim through the Da'wah(دعوة) of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
So he was a blessed man and this relates to the personality of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
He was very social, very likable, very approachable.
He was very good in his social skills, he had a very wide social network,
very well known all over Arabia, he knows a lot about others.
Therefore this opens the lines of communication between him and other tribes.
See, when you know about the background of the people that facilitates, your conversation with them.
So, Abu Bakr As-Siddique  رضي الله عنه.
كان نصابة
He was a scholar of his time in genealogy.
So, he knew the names of the tribes, their locations, their qualities, the pros and cons of each tribe,
and you can find that he is very prevalent in his discussions with others.
Naturally Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه, had to go through the persecution that the Muslims, went through.
Allahسبحانه وتعالى tested them, and He tested him, like everyone else.
When the Muslims reached 38 in number.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه went to Muhammadﷺ and said;
Messenger of Allah! We should proclaim the message publicly,
up to that stage, the Da'wah(دعوة) was done, secretly.
Rasool Allah ﷺ would invite his close associates.
People whom he trusts, and he would never make a public announcement of it.
Because of the danger and risk in those early days of Da'wah(دعوة).
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه felt that we have reached a stage
where our numbers qualify us to publicly proclaim the message.
So, he goes to Muhammadﷺ and says,
O Messenger of Allah, We want to make Istelaan(إستعلان), Istalan(إستعلن), make the message public.
Rasool Allah ﷺ responded by saying,
"إنَّ قليل"
We are few, in number.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه kept on insisting on Rasool Allah ﷺ, until the Messenger of Allah agreed.
Rasool Allah ﷺ would lend an open ear to the advice of Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق),
the relationship between them was so close.
And only Allah knows the conversations that went between them,
see Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه has not narrated many Ahadith(احاديث),
because Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه passed away very early on, in Islam, two years after the death of Muhammadﷺ.
So, we really don't know what went on between them.
I mean, Rasool Allah ﷺ and Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) has spent hours and hours and hours together, a lot of time.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ accepted the advice of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
So, they went into the Masjid(مسجد), where all of the Mushrikeen(مشركين) are gathered
and the Sahabah(صحابه) spread around the Masjid(مسجد),
and Rasool Allah ﷺ was sitting next to Abu Bakr(ابوبكر), while Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) was standing.
And Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه delivered the speech,
and that was the first public speech ever delivered in Islam.
Therefore Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) is not only the first Muslim
and the first after the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) to enter into Jannah(جنة),
and the greatest of the Al-Mo'minoon(مؤمنون), and the first Khalifah(خليفه),
but he's also the first public speaker in Islam.
He stood up and he proclaimed the Shahadah(شهادة) of,
"لا اله الا الله محمد رسول الله "
You can obviously imagine the response.
The Mushrikeen(مشركين) attacked, and their point of attack was.?
The speaker! Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق).
They all jumped on him.
They did attack the others but the focus of their attack was Abu Bakr رضي الله عنه.
Among the attackers was Ut'ba Bin Rabiyah(عتبة بن ربيعة),
who after he threw Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) to the ground, he took off his shoes
and he started hitting Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) in the face, and pressing the shoes in the face of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
And it wasn't until Bannu Taim(بنوتيم), the tribe of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) came in and interfered and pushed away the attackers,
the attack stopped, otherwise Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) would have died.
Because they have disfigured his face
so you cannot tell his nose, from the rest of the face, covered in blood.
They carried him back home, and the men of Taim(تيم), alongside the father of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) were standing around him.
They thought that his death was certain.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه, his face was disfigured, body injured, and he lost consciousness.
So they went to Ut'ba(عتبة), and they said;
If our man dies then we're going to kill Ut'ba(عتبة).
And that would have sparked a war in Quraish(قريش),
because you know the tribal system, you kill one of ours, we kill one of yours, that's how it works.
This is serious, among tribes, they don't take this lightly.
Bannu Taim(بنوتيم) even though, they were considered to be a small clan in Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), not one of the strong clans.
But they said if our man dies and even though these were all Mushrikeen(مشركين),
if our man dies, we're gonna kill Ut'ba(عتبة).
Hours later, Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) regained consciousness.
And what was the first thing he said;
ما فعل رسول الله
What happened to Rasool Allah ﷺ.?
What happened to the Messenger of Allah.?
Now you can only imagine the response of Bannu Taim(بنوتيم).
They started cursing Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق), yelling at him.
The way they saw this, is that you got into this trouble because you followed Muhammad ﷺthis man, who brought us disunity.
See the kuffar(كفار) of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), they would always accuse Muhammad(محمد) of bringing disunity among them
and making them break ties to their kinship.
Because in one family, you would have Muslims and non Muslims and that caused the Rift,
from the top of the society down to each individual family.
So, they said, they used to always say,
"فرَّقَّ جَمَاعْتَنَا"
This is the man, who brought us disunity.
Allahعَزّوجَلّ has called Qur'an, Furqaan(فرقان), it separates between good and evil.
So that break apart was happening, even on the level of the family.
Some people will choose Al-Haqq(الحق), some people will choose Al-Batil(الباطل).
Bannu Taim(بنوتيم) were upset with Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه because they said:
You got into this trouble because of Muhammadﷺ
we were going to have to fight a war if you died because of the trouble of Muhammadﷺ.
And now, as soon as you wake up rather than taking care of yourself and taking care of your tribe.
You ask about what happened to Muhammadﷺ, when you're on the verge of death.
So they were very angered by that statement and they walked out.
And this was very difficult, I mean, that's not pressure that any one of us could handle.
You get into trouble because of Da'wah(دعوة)
and then you are still willing to publicly state that even after all this happened to me,
all what I care about is Muhammadﷺ.
So they left him, Abu Qahafah(ابوقحافه), the father of Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه left
and he told the mother of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) to feed him.
So the mother of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) brought in, some food and water to her son, Abu Bakr As-Siddique.
He asked her, How is Muhammadﷺ.?
She said: My son I have no idea about Muhammadﷺ, eat some food and drink.
He said: My mother go to Umm Jameel Bint Al-Khattab(أم جميل بنت ألخطاب) and ask her about Muhammadﷺ.
So she went to Umm Jameel(ام جميل), and she asked her.
My son is asking you how is Muhammadﷺ.?
So, she responded by saying and look at the response of Umm Jameel(ام جميل),
because Umm Jameel(ام جميل) was Muslim in secret, it wasn't public.
She said: I have no idea about Muhammadﷺ and I have no idea about your son.
I know nothing about them.
She had to protect herself because, again, in that stage the Muslims were very few and weak
and the mother of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) wasn't Muslim, so she said;
I have no idea about Muhammadﷺ and I have no idea about Abu Bakr(ابوبكر), I don't know anything about them.
But if you want, I can go and see your son.
So she wants to protect herself but in the same time, she's concerned about Abu Bakr As-Siddiqueرضي الله عنه.
So she went alongside the mother of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
And Umm Jameel(ام جميل) as soon as she saw Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه in the stage, he was in.
She screamed.! And she said;
People who did this to you are an evil people.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه said, O Umm Jameel(ام جميل), how is Muhammadﷺ.?
Umm Jameel(ام جميل) said: Your mother is listening, your mother is here.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique(أبوبكرالصديق) said: Don't worry about her, speak.
Even though the mother of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) wasn't Muslim, but his family is trustworthy,
and you can speak in front of my mother.
She said: Muhammadﷺ is healthy and fine.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه said: I am not going to eat anything, nor will I drink anything, until you're taking me to him
I want to see Muhammadﷺ.
So, they took Abu Bakr As-Siddique(أبوبكرالصديق) at night, hours later,
and they had to carry him because again he cannot even walk.
They had to carry him on their shoulders and it was late at night.
And as soon as they came in to the place where Rasool Allah ﷺ and the Sahabah(صحابه) were sitting,
immediately Rasool Allah ﷺ stood up and kissed Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه,
when he saw his state, and he felt very sorry for him.
What did Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه say.?
Did he say, O Rasool Allah ﷺ, I suffered so much for you.?
O messenger of Allah, I'm, in pain, I'm aching.
O Messenger of Allah, I was about to die.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه said: O Messenger of Allah
There is no harm in me, whatsoever, I'm feeling no pain, whatsoever.
It's just this small injury in my face, That's it.!
إِلَّا ابْتِغَاءَ وَجْهِ رَبِّهِ الْأَعْلَىٰ۝
He's doing everything, for the sake of Allahعَزّوجَلّ.
So, Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه, was an example of sacrifice to the limit,
giving everything for the sake of Allahعَزّوجَلّ.
One of the Sahabah(صحابه) Abdullah Bin Amr Bin Aas(عبدالله بن عمروبن ألعاص) was asked by Tabaeen(تابعين).
What is the worst thing you have seen in the persecution of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) to Muhammadﷺ.?
What is the worst thing, that you have seen, you have witnessed.?
I mean Rasool Allah ﷺ, went through a lot, but tell us about something that you have witnessed yourself,
Abdullah Bin Amr Bin Aas(عبدالله بن عمروبن ألعاص), one of the early Muslims.
He said: One day, I saw the Mushrikeen(مشركين) of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) attack Muhammadﷺ.
And they're grabbing him, pulling him and yelling at him, fighting him.
And then I saw Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه pulling them, and pushing them, away and saying,
أتقتلون الرجل أن يقول ربي الله
Are you killing a man just because he says, My lord is Allah.?
And this is in Bukhari(بخاريْ),
and there's another narration that could be talking about the same incident.
Asma Bin Abi Bakr رضي الله عنها said; We're once at home.
So, somebody came to us and spoke to my father and said: Go and help your friend - Muhammadﷺ.
So Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) immediately rushed.
Asma(اسماء) said; Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) had four braids, they used to tie their hair.
So, he went to help Rasool Allah ﷺ, and he was pushing the people away from Muhammadﷺ alone,
see this huge group was attacking Muhammadﷺ
and Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) alone was trying to push them away.
And he's saying
أتقتلون الرجل أن يقول ربي الله
Are you killing a man, just because he says that Allah is my Lord.
And then they attacked Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه and they left Muhammadﷺ.
And he kept on fighting with them.
And when he came back, his braids and his hair whenever he would touch it, it would fall away, fall down.
The Sahabahرضي الله عنهم, they all admitted the status of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر)
and they recognized the high, noble stage Abu Bakr As-Siddique(أبوبكرالصديق) was at.
Ali Bin Abi Talib رضي الله عنه years after Abu Bakr As-Siddique(أبوبكرالصديق) passed away.
He was standing on the pulpit, on Al-Mimber(الممبر),
when he was Khalifah(خليفه), when he was Khalifah(خليفه), when he was Ameer Ul Momineen(أميرالمؤمنين).
And I also want you to notice the gratitude of the Sahabah(صحابه),
the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم were very grateful people,
they that no pride, no arrogance, very simple.
So, Ali Bin Abi Talib(علي بن ابي طالب), who's the Khalifah(خليفه) now, Ameer Ul Momineen(امير المؤمنين),
he's standing on Al-Mimber(الممبر), And he's asking his followers the following question.?
أيها الناس من ألشَجَعُ ألناس
Who is the most brave and courageous of men.
What would you expect the answer to be.? You!
Ali Bin Abi Talib رضي الله عنه was recognized as the most courageous.
And that wasn't something that anyone would dispute, the courage of Ali Bin Abi Talib(علي بن ابي طالب)
فارس من فرسان لِلْاِسلام
And his stories in courage, are well known.
So, they said: You are the most courageous of men.
Ali Bin Abi Talib(علي بن ابي طالب) said: I have never faced an opponent and lost,
I have never faced an opponent one to one and lost.
But the most courageous of men, is Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه.
He said: In the Battle of Badr(بدر), we built a shed for Rasool Allah ﷺ.
And we asked for a volunteer
to be the security guard of Muhammadﷺ on that difficult day.
And the only one, who was there was Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه,
and I could see him holding his sword in his hand
going around the tent of Rasool Allah ﷺ guarding him, from every direction,
Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) is the most courageous of men.!
And then he said: And one day in Makkah,
when the enemies of Allah, attacked Rasool Allah ﷺ from every direction
no one went to help Rasool Allah ﷺ, but Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) and it was pushing the kuffar(كفار) away and saying,
أتقتلون الرجل أن يقول ربي الله
Are you killing a man just because he says, My Lord is Allah.?
Now there's a story in Qur'an that talks about
a very righteous man called Mo'min Aal-Firaun(مؤمن آلفرعون), in Surat Ghafir(سورة الغافر).
Very long story talking about a member of the family of Firaun(فرعون), who became a believer.
And Qur'an gives a long narration of his story.
Ali Bin Abi Talib(علي بن ابي طالب), after he mentioned these two events,
the one in Badr(بدر) and the one in Makkah.
He started crying, and he covered his face,
with his clothes and he soaked them with tears,
because it's brought back the memories of Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه,
look at the love that he had for Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق).
He said: I ask you in the name of Allah to tell me, who is better.
The Mo'min(مؤمن) of Firaun(فرعون) or Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق).
فسكت الْقَوم
Everybody was quiet.
Ali Bin Abi Talib(علي بن ابي طالب) said: In the name of Allah,
One hour in the life of Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه
is more worthy than the whole world filled with the Mo'min(مؤمن) of Firaun(فرعون),
that was Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه.
Ibn Kathir(ابن كثير) stated that when Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) became Muslim,
his wealth was for the service of Islam.
During the years of Da'wah(دعوة) in Makkah.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه would use his money to support Muhammadﷺ
and to support anybody, who is in need among the new forming community of Muslims.
Bilal Ibn Rabah(بلال ابن رباح) was a person, who was cut off from the society around him.
He was a foreigner, from Africa going through servitude,
with one of the worst figures in Makkah, Umayyah Bin Khalaf(امية بن خلف), one of the tyrants of Quraish(قريش).
Nevertheless, he became muslim, a foreigner, a slave, enslaved by one of the most impressive men in Quraish(قريش)
and he still had the courage to say,
أشهد و الله اله الا الله، واشهدو ان محمد الرسول الله
In fact one of the Sahabah(صحابه) says,
every single one of the weak among the Sahabah(صحابه) did give in,
at one point or another to the demands of the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), except Bilal(بلال).
He never compromised, he never gave in,
even though they were excused under coercion, in the state of Ikrah(اقراح).
If you're forced, if you're coerced, then Allahعَزّوجَلّ will excuse you
but Bilal Ibn Rabah(بلال ابن رباح) never gave in.
So, Umayyah Bin Khalaf(امية بن خلف) would have him starve for an entire day, deprive him of food.
And then he would send him out at noontime to the desert surrounding Makkah.
He would have him lay on his bare back on the hot sand
and then he would order his servants to carry a huge rock,
and to place it, on the chest of Bilal(بلال), and to leave him in that status.
And he would tell Bilal(بلال), I'm going to keep you that way, until you die.
Or you give up the religion of Muhammadﷺ.
What would Bilal(بلال) say,
"أحدٌ أحد"
Allah is One! Allah is One!
Later on, the Muslims would ask Bilal(بلال), how come that was your slogan,
"أحدٌ أحد"
I mean, why did you particularly choose that word to repeat again and again?
What did Bilal(بلال), say.?
He said: Because I realized that, that is the word that angers Umayyah(امية), the most.
He wasn't trying to appease Umayyah Bin Khalaf(امية بن خلف).
He wasn't trying to ease the pain on him.
He said that word made him the most angry and that's why I was saying it again and again.
أحدٌ أحد
I really prayed to Allahعَزّوجَلّ that Allah gives us that spirit, which we have lost.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه he went out of Makkah to the punishment spot of Bilal(بلال).
And he went to bargain and negotiate with Umayyah Bin Khalaf(امية بن خلف).
He told him, until when are you keep on persecuting this man?
Umayyah Bin Khalaf(امية بن خلف) said;
It is because of you, therefore you take care of this problem, you are the ones, who caused this in the first place.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه said: Would you sell him to me?
He said: Yes, I would.
For how much?
In one narration, it says 40 Ouqia(أوقيه), of gold.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه said and I accept it.
Umayyah Bin Khalaf(امية بن خلف) said: If you would have refused
I would have sold him to you for half that price.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه said;
If you would have asked me for double that price I would have paid it.
So, he bought Bilal(بلال) so now Bilal(بلال), is the ownership of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر),
he immediately freed him, now you're free.
Later on, the Sahabah(صحابه) would say,
سيِّدُنَا أعْتَقه سيِّدِنا
A noble man has freed our noble man.
Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) has freed Bilal(بلال), both of them are Syed(سيد), both of them are noble men.
Bilal Ibn Rabah(بلال ابن رباح), the slave was considered to be among the nobility of the Muslims,
the Mu'azzin(مؤذن) of Rasool Allah ﷺ, one of the great Mujahideen(مجاهدين).
سيِّدُنَا أعْتَقه سيِّدِنا
There was another slave, her name is Zanneera(زنيره).
It says, Wallah Aalam(والله أعلم) if this is true that she was a European slave from Europe, a Roman,
in Arabia, slavery would cross, the color boundaries, I mean, a slave could be any color.
It wasn't like the European slavery and the American slavery that was color based, based on discrimination.
In Arabia, it didn't depend on the color.
It depends on whether you're taken as a captive in war.
If you are white, black, Arab, it doesn't make a difference.
If you can't pay your dues, you become a slave, no matter which background you come from.
Zaid Bin Harisaa(زيد بن حارثه) was an Arab and he was a slave.
Sohaib Ar-Roomi(صهيب الرومي) was a Roman and he was a slave.
Salman Al-Farsi(سلمان الفارسي) was Persian and he was a slave.
Bilal(بلال), was African and he was a slave.
So therefore, when the orientalist talk about slavery in Islam it's a completely different thing.
They're comparing it to their version of slavery, which is the Based on ethnic discrimination, based on color,
while the slavery that existed in Islam,
when we say existed in Islam, in reality, Islam has freed more slaves than any other religion in the world.
When you look at the total number of slaves who came into Islam, and were freed,
because of all of the rules and regulations in Islam,
and the fact that many forms of punishment include freeing a slave,
the Muslims have ended up freeing more slaves than any other nation in the world.
Zanneera(زنيره) was also purchased by Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه and he freed her.
As soon as she was freed.
Subhan Allah(سبحان الله) look at the test of Allah.
When she became Muslim, she lost her sight.
So, the Mushrikeen(مشركين) said, Al-Laat(الآت) and Al-Uzza(العزة) took away her sight,
as a punishment for her from the gods.
It was A test for Zanneera(زنيره), to see how firm her Eeman(ايمان) was.
Zanneera(زنيره) said: No! It is Allah, Who gives sight
and who takes it away and it's not Al-Laat(الآت) Wal-Uzza(العزة),
immediately she got her sight back, the test was over.
Allah سبحانه وتعالى tested her, she passed the test, so Allah gave her, her sight back.
She was also freed by Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه.
Aamir Bin Fuhaira(عامر بن فحيره) another slave, who was persecuted,
purchased by Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) and then freed by him.
And he later on became the servant of Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه
and he died as a Shaheed رضي الله عنه, Aamir Bin Fuhaira(عامر بن فحيره).
An-Nahdiyyah(النهديه) and her daughter were slaves with one of the Mushrik(مشرك) women of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ)
and she would put them through strenuous and very tough work.
So, Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه came and offered to purchase them from the owner.
So she agreed, and Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) later on freed them.
Then there was Jariat Bannu Muammal(جاريت بنو معمل), who were from the tribe of Bannu Udae(بنو عدي),
the tribe of Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب),
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) volunteered to punish this woman, she wasn't his slave.
But he hated Islam so much, he volunteered to torment her.
So he would go and punish her and then when he would get tired,
he would say, Listen, I'm not giving you a break because I'm having mercy on you.
I'm doing it because I'm tired.
He doesn't want to give her any break, and then he tells her,
and then she responds by saying it is Allah, Who made you give me a break.
Allahعَزّوجَلّ is the one, who made you get tired and exhausted.
Abu Bakr رضي الله عنه purchased her and freed her.
This became a joke among the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
They made fun of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر), they considered him foolish.
Why.?
The tradition was in, among them that when you free a slave,
that slave retains a relationship of loyalty with the one, who freed them.
So, if a slave is freed out of gratitude,
they have this very close relationship with the one who freed them and it's a loyal relationship.
And supposedly you should offer protection for the one, who freed you.
Therefore, they would only free, strong people, if they see a slave, who has some potential.
They would free that person because this person if they become free, they could be a protection for you.
So, the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) were making fun of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر),
why was he freeing these women and weak men, who are going to do him nothing, no good.
? In fact, the father of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) came to me and said:
My son, I find you freeing these weak people.
How come you don't free some strong men so that they will help you in the future.
Abu Bakr As-Siddique(ابوبكرالصديق) responded by saying,
I'm doing this for the sake of Allah and not for the sake of Duniyah(دنيا).
And these are the reason for the revelation of the Ayaat(آيات) of Surat Al-Lail(سورة اليل) that we talked about,
وَسَيُجَنَّبُهَا الْأَتْقَى۝
الَّذِي يُؤْتِي مَالَهُ يَتَزَكَّىٰ۝
وَمَا لِأَحَدٍ عِندَهُ مِن نِّعْمَةٍ تُجْزَىٰ۝
إِلَّا ابْتِغَاءَ وَجْهِ رَبِّهِ الْأَعْلَىٰ۝وَلَسَوْفَ يَرْضَىٰ۝
It says that the one, who will be spared from the fire is the one, who is Atqaa(أتقى)
one of the name of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) is Atqaa(أتقى), the most pious one.
The one, who gives for the sake of Allah, seeking no payback in Duniyah(دنيا).
He is doing it for Allah, he is not doing it,
so that he will have some strong men, who would stand for him.
He's doing it to please Allah.
And then the last Ayaah(آية) in the Surah(سورة) says,
وَلَسَوْفَ يَرْضَىٰ
Allah will please him, Allah will make Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) happy, it's a promise from Allahعَزّوجَلّ.